Newman, Donald J.; Papers ua902.024
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Donald J. Newman Papers
1954-1989
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Newman, Donald J.
ua902.024
6.0 cubic ft.
The Donald J. Newman Papers document the career of the Professor of Criminal Justice and Dean of the School of Criminal Justice (1977-1984) including correspondence, subject files, adminstrative records, evaluations of other universities and his criminal justice projects.
Access
Access to these records is unrestricted except where otherwise noted in the finding aid.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Biographical Sketch
Donald J. Newman was born in Janesville, Wisconsin, on June 4, 1924, the son of Kendell and Catherine (Mahoney) Newman. Raised in Janesville Dr. Newman served in the Army from 1943 to 1946. After the army he returned to Wisconsin and attended the University of Wisconsin where he received his bachelor's in psychology (1949), a master's in sociology (1952) and a Ph.D, also in sociology (1954). In 1949 Dr. Newman married Evelyn S. Zatlin, they later had two sons and one daughter.
Dr. Newman began his professional career teaching sociology at St. Lawrence University in Canton New York from 1953 until 1960. He then returned to the University of Wisconsin where he taught law and social work until 1967. In 1967 Dr. Newman became a professor of criminal justice at SUNY Albany. He served as Dean of the School of Criminal Justice from 1977 until 1984 when both health problems and disagreements over the inclusion of the school with the administrative framework of Rockefeller College lead to his resignation as Dean. He continued to serve as a professor in the School of Criminal Justice until his death.
In addition to his teaching Dr. Newman did extensive consulting work with groups such as the U.S. Justice Department (1971), the New York Department of Corrections (1971-1972), and the Police Foundation (1978). Along with this he helped shape the direction of criminal justice education through his evaluations of the programs in numerous schools including The University of Nebraska (1976), The University of Minnesota (1978) and the University of Illinois at Chicago (1984)
Throughout his career Dr. Newman remained interested in plea bargaining, parole and prison conditions, areas in which he was considered the national authority. Other areas of interest included juvenile delinquency, policing and later in his career elderly criminals.
Dr. Newman was the author of five books: Conviction: The Determination of Guilt or Innocence Without Trial (1966), Criminal Justice Administration (1969,82), Introduction to Criminal Justice (1975, 1978, 1986, 1989), Elderly Criminals (1984), and Principles of Criminal Justice (1984).
Dr. Newman and his first wife were divorced in March 1987. He later remarried Katherine Blueglass. Dr. Newman died of a stroke on January 26, 1990 at the age of 65 in Albany N.Y.**
Note: ** Biographical information taken from Who's Who In America 1988-1989 ed., vol.2 P. 2282 and Dr. Newman's obituary in the New York Times Jan 31, 1990 p.D27.
Scope and Contents
The Donald J. Newman Papers span from 1954 to 1989. However the bulk of the material spans the period from 1967, the start of his career at SUNY, to the summer of 1983, when Dr. Newman began to face serious medical problems.
While Dr. Newman performed extensive consulting work with private criminal justice foundations and law enforcement agencies during his career, there are no files relating to this. However, there are records dealing with evaluations he conducted for universities and colleges, including, in most cases, copies of the evaluations themselves.
The School of Criminal Justice Records consist of Dr. Newman's personal copies of internal documents relating to his service on School Committees. For the files that he kept while serving as Dean, 1977-1983, see the School of Criminal Justice Records.
The Criminal Justice Projects series contains the records of numerous projects that Dr. Newman worked on throughout his career. These records reflect his interest in prison reform, policing, and juvenile delinquency. However a large portion of the material consists of reports and studies published by state agencies and used as references by Dr. Newman. This series does not contain any of his published material. Also absent are any files relating to his interest in elderly criminals.
See also the records of the School of Criminal Justice and the Richard Myren Papers.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - Dean's Correspondence, 1954-1989
Series 2 - School of Criminal Justice Records, 1966-1989
Series 3 - Criminal Justice Projects, 1959-1983
All series are arranged alphabetically.
Criminal Justice and Prisons; Criminology--Research; Criminology--Study and teaching; Universities and colleges--Administration; College administrators; Albany (N.Y.); Correspondence; Memorandums; Minutes; Administrative reports; Proposals; Grant proposals; UAlbany Faculty & Alumni Papers; Newman, Donald J., 1924-1990; State University of New York at Albany. School of Criminal Justice
- Correspondence File, 1954-1989; 1; 3.0 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains correspondence between Dr. Newman as Dean with faculty and prospective faculty as well as with students, former students, friends, and colleagues about their careers and projects. The files on individuals often contain correspondence that dates before his appointment as Acting Dean in 1977. Included are correspondence with famed criminologist Marvin E. Wolfgang (1961-83) and the former Dean of the School of Criminal Justice and School President Vincent O'Leary (1968-77). The bulk of the material dates between 1968 and 1983.
  See also the Donald Newman Papers correspondence file for additional correspondence with students and colleagues
  - Berkshire Community College, Evaluation, 1986 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 1)
  - Chappell, Duncun, 1969-1974 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 2)
  - Clinard, Marshall B., 1954-1984 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 3)
  - Correctional Grant Proposal, 1971 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 4)
  - Cosgrove, Colleen, 1975-1977 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 5)
  - Criminal Justice Educators Grant, 1974 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 6)
  - Dickson, Carlisle, 1975-1976 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 7)
  - "Diversion from Criminal Processing", a study, 1971 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 8)
  - Humphries, H. Laud, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 9)
  - Innovation Proseminars, Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 10)
  - Institute for Public Policy Alternatives (IPPA) Reprimand for Student Publication, 1975 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 11)
  - O'Neill, Michael, 1970 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 12)
  - Pacht, Asher, 1964-1966 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 13)
  - Pasciuto, Anthony, 1972-1976 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 14)
  - Pinkerton Chair, 1970 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 15)
  - Powers, Sanger B., 1958-1972 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 16)
  - Preiser Interview, 1974 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 17)
  - Prigmore, Charles, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 18)
  - Scheff, Thomas, 1962-1965 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 19-20)
  - Schwartz, Herman, 1975 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 21)
  - Schwartz, Martin, 1975-1977 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 22)
  - Shin, H. Joo - Drug Abuse Evaluations, 1970-1977 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 23)
  - Shireman, Charles H., 1963 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 24)
  - Short, James, 1968 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 25)
  - Student Correspondence Re: Dissertations, 1969-1974 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 26)
  - Summer Institute for Outside Criminal Justice Faculty, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 27)
  - Undergraduate Studies Committee, 1989 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 28)
  - University Senate, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 29)
  - Walker, Nigel, 1974 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 30)
  - Walsh, Marilyn, 1975-1977 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 31)
  - Weisenhorn, Donald J. - Sam Houston State University, 1971-1972 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 32)
  - Wells, George - McNeese State University, 1976 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 33)
  - Westerlund, Ronald, 1960-1968 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 34)
  - Wisconsin, University of - Milwaukee Evaluation, 1984 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence File), Folder 35)
- School of Criminal Justice Records, 1966-1989; 2; 0.33 cubic ft.
  Consist primarily of retained records of the Council of Deans (1980-81), SCJ Faculty Meeting minutes (1977-1981), as well as files relating to faculty merit increases, recruitment, salaries, work load. See also the Donald Newman Papers School of Criminal Justice File for his collection of SCJ faculty meeting minutes (1968-, 1984-89), and committee minutes. Additional records in this series include:
  Correspondence File, Chiefly correspondence with students, friends and colleagues about their careers and projects
  School of Criminal Justice File, 1966-89 .66 cubic ft. Arranged alphabetically by subject. Contains memorandum, notes and letters pertaining to the School of Criminal Justice. Includes SCJ Dean's Reports (1968-69, 1971-72, 1973-74), SCJ Faculty Meeting Minutes (1968-74, 1984-89), SCJ By-Laws (1968-69), as well as Admission Committee, Curriculum Committee, and records relating to his chairmanship of the SCJ Faculty, 1972-74.
  - School of Criminal Justice File, 1966-1989; 2.1
    - Admissions Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 1 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 1)
    - Chairman of the Faculty, 1972-1974 (Box 1 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 2-3)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1986-1987 (Box 1 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 4)
    - Curriculum and Educational Policy Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 1 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 5-6)
    - Excellence Awards, 1988-1989 (Box 1 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 7)
    - Masters Degree Project, 1969 (Box 1 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 8)
    - SCJ By-Law Committee, 1968-1989 (Box 1 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 9)
    - SCJ Dean's Report, 1968-1969; 1971-1974 (Box 1 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 10-12)
    - SCJ Faculty Meeting, 1969-1974; 1984-1989 (Box 1 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 13-24)
    - SCJ Faculty Search, 1984-1985 (Box 1 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 25)
    - SCJ Former Students, 1968-1973 (Box 1 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 26)
    - SCJ Outside Funding, 1968 (Box 1 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 27)
    - SCJ Retreat, 1974 (Box 1 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 28)
    - SCJ Review, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 29)
    - SCJ Review Committee, 1974 (Box 1 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 30)
    - SCJ Status Report, 1966-1968 (Box 1 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 31)
    - Student School Evaluations, 1975 (Box 1 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 32)
  - Dean's Correspondence File, 1977-1983; 2.2
    - Acker, James R., 1982-1983 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 1)
    - Administrative Interset Group, 1979-1980 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 2)
    - Alaksa, University of, Evaluation, 1978 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 3)
    - American University, Evaluation, 1981 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 4)
    - Austin, Dr. W. Timothy, 1981 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 5)
    - Chicago, University of Illinois at, Evaluation, 1984 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 6)
    - Citizens Crime Commission of N.Y.C., Inc. (Eliot Lumbard), 1978 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 7)
    - Clarke, R.V.G., 1981-1983 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 8)
    - Cohen, Fred, 1964-1983 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 9)
    - Cutshall, Charles, 1982 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 10)
    - Duffee, David, 1974-1983 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 11)
    - Elliston, Fred, 1980 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 12)
    - Engle, Donald, 1977-1987 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 13)
    - Farnworth, Margaret, 1983 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 14)
    - Farrell, Ron, 1982-1983 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 15)
    - Felkenes, George - Michigan State University, 1977-1980 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 16)
    - Flanagan, Tim, 1982-1983 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 17)
    - Florida International University, Evaluation, 1977 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 18)
    - Foley, Denis - Post-Doctoral Fellow, 1977-1979 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 19)
    - Foster, Price, 1976-1985 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 20)
    - Fox, James W., 1976-1980 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 21)
    - Georges, Daniel, 1977-1979 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 22)
    - Goldkamp, John - Temple University, 1980-1981 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 23)
    - Gottfredson, Don, 1976-1983 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 24)
    - Gottfredson, Michael, 1979-1981 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 25)
    - Hardt, Robert, 1961-1983 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 26)
    - Hindelang, Michael J., 1970-1982 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 27)
    - Hindelang, Michael J. - Memorial Scholarship Fund, 1982 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 28)
    - Hirschi, Travis, 1976-1981 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 29)
    - Ilchman, Warren, 1980 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 30)
    - In-Hak, Yoo, 1980-1981 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 31)
    - Kenefick, Donald P., 1979-1980 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 32)
    - Kirk, Stuart A., 1980 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 33)
    - Kress, Jack, 1973-1981 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 34)
    - Landau, Shima, 1977-1978 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 35)
    - Lejins, Peter, 1957-1980 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 36)
    - Levine, Howard, 1979-1982 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 37)
    - Lofton, Colin, 1979-1982 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 38)
    - Lumbard Award, 1981-1982 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 39)
    - Lumbard, Eliot H., 1975-1983 (Box 2 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 40)
    - MacDonald, Donald G., 1977-1978 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 1)
    - Malinchak, Alan A., 1983 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 2)
    - Manning, Peter K., 1981-1982 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 3)
    - Martin, John M., 1967 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 4)
    - Massachusetts Department of Youth Services, 1982 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 5)
    - Massachusetts Parole Board, 1971 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 6)
    - McAnany, Patrick, 1978 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 7)
    - McCarthy, Brian, 1976-1978 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 8)
    - McCleary, Richard, 1981-1983 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 9)
    - McConville, S.D.M., 1981-1982 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 10)
    - Mcleod, Lynne, 1972-1977 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 11)
    - McNeese State University, 1976 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 12)
    - McNulty, John - Alabny County Sheriff, 1978-1979 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 13)
    - Minnesota, University of, Evaluation, 1978-1979 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1975-1976; 1978-1982 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 15-18)
    - Morgan, John, 1977-1983 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 19)
    - Morgenbesser, Leonard, 1975-1982 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 20)
    - Munro, Jim, 1974-1980 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 21)
    - Murphy, Patrick V., 1982-1983 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 22)
    - Murphy, Patrick - Commissioner N.Y.P.D., 1970-1971 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 23)
    - Nebraska, University, Evaluation, 1976 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 24)
    - NeMoyer, Edgar, ca. 1962-1972 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 25)
    - Newman, Graeme, 1972-1983 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 26)
    - North Carolina Central University, 1981 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 27)
    - N.S.F. Study, 1972 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 28)
    - N.Y.C. Police Alumni, 1978 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 29)
    - Nygoard, Alvin, 1962-1963 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 30)
    - N.Y.S.Criminal Justice Educators, 1973 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 31)
    - N.Y.S. Police, 1970 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 32)
    - Oetting, Edward - SUNY Archivist, 1983 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 33)
    - O'Leary, Vincent - President SUNY Albany, 1968-1977 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 34)
    - Palmer, Ted B., 1980 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 35)
    - Pelfrey, William V., 1981-1982 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 36)
    - Pennsylvania, University of, 1978 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 37)
    - Pierce, Lawrence W., The Honorable, 1969-1981 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 38)
    - Pochoda, Dan, 1981-1982 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 39)
    - Police Executive Research Forum (P.E.R.F.) - Gary P. Haynes Exec. Dir., 1980 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 40)
    - Pope, Carl, 1975-1988 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 41)
    - Provost/Resignation of Deanship, 1983-1984 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 42)
    - Punch, Maurice, 1981-1982 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 43)
    - Rafter, Nicole Hahn, 1971-1989 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 44)
    - Redl, Fritz, 1974-1981 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 45)
    - Robinson, Cyril, 1966-1977 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 46)
    - Robinson, Edward, 1978 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 47)
    - Rosenbaum, Larry, 1972-1980 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 48)
    - Rubin, H. Ted, 1978-1979 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 49)
    - Rucinski, Lady R., 1979 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 50)
    - Rutgers, State University of N.J., 1972-1980 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 51)
    - Ryan, Edward, 1970-1982 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 52)
    - Salas, Luis, 1979-1982 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 53)
    - Sherman, Lawrence, 1977-1983 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 54)
    - Shoham, Shlomo, 1977 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 55)
    - Smith, Beverly Ann, 1979-1983 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 56)
    - Smith, Christopher J., 1981 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 57)
    - Smith, Dwight, 1980 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 58-59)
    - Southern Vermont College, Bennington VT - Dean William Glassner, 1981 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 60)
    - Student Association, 1979 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 61)
    - SUNY Press, 1980-1983 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 62-64)
    - Toch, Hans, 1969-1981 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 65)
    - Under Cover, 1980-1981 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 66)
    - Validation Project, 1979 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 67)
    - Van Den Haag, Ernest, 1978-1983 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 68)
    - Vandervort, Lucinda A., 1980-1983 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 69)
    - Walker, Samuel, 1979 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 70)
    - Waller, Irvin, 1979-1982 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 71)
    - Warren, Marguerite, 1973-1983 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 72)
    - Watson, James, 1980 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 73)
    - Weinberg, Martin S., 1960-1981 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 74)
    - Wilbanks, Bill, 1972-1983 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 75)
    - Wilkins, Leslie, 1968-1983 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 76)
    - Wilkins, Leslie Awards Committee, 1980-1982 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 77)
    - Witt, James, 1977-1980 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 78)
    - Wolfgang, Marvin E., 1961-1983 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 79)
    - Zalman, Marvin, 1973-1983 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 80)
  - Dean's Subject Files, 1977-1983; 2.3
    - Dean's Council Meetings, 1980-1981 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 81-82)
    - Faculty Committees, 1979-1981 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 83-84)
    - Faculty Meetings, 1977-1981 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 85-88)
    - Faculty Recruitment Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 89)
    - Faculty Salaries, 1971-1981 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 90)
    - Faculty Workload, April 1981 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 91)
    - Merit Increases, 1981 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 92)
    - Rockefeller College - Executive Committee Meetings, 1981 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 93)
    - SCJ Alumni Directory, 1977 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 94)
    - SCJ Students, 1980 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 95)
    - School Plans, 1981 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 96)
    - Teaching Assistant, 1980 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 97)
    - Tenure and Promotion, 1980-1982 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 98)
    - University Faculty Salaries, 1971-1981 (Box 3 (2-School of Criminal Justice Records), Folder 99)
- Criminal Justice Projects, 1959-1983; 3; 2.0 cubic ft.
  Arranged aphabetically by subject.